Henry F. Dobyns Papers 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Correspondence, 1918-2008
  - Tucson Council for Civic Unity, 1950-1951, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - The Tucson Presidio and the Apaches in 1830, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Turner, Allen C., 1970-1975 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Turner, Allen C., 1976-1983 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - U, 1957-2000 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
  - Ubelaker, Douglas, 1975-1993 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Udall, Morris, 1971-1982 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Udall, Stewart, 1954-1986 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - University of Arizona, 1945-1959 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - University of Arizona Press, 1974-2001 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - University of Arizona Press- Spanish Colonial Tucson, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1963-1974 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1983-1996 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - University of Oklahoma Press- Fortunes in Feathers, 1989-1992 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - University of Tennessee Press, 1980-1982 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - University of Tennessee Press, 1983-1995 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - University of Wisconsin- Parkside- Appointment, 1980-1983 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Unrau, William, 1973-1990 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Upham, Steadman, 1983-1993 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - V, 1939-1994 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Vandiveer, William, 1980-1983 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Vásquez, Nadine, 1976-1987 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - W, 1947-2004 (Box 24, Folder 23-24)
  - W, 1947-2004 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Wagner, Erika, 1971-1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Walker, Deward, 1967-1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Ward, Albert, 1971-1979 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Ward, Albert, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ward, Albert, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Ward, Albert, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Ward, Albert, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
  - Ward, Albert, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Ward, Albert, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Ward, Albert, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Ward, Albert, 1989-1991 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Ward, Albert, 1992-1996 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Ward, Albert, 1997-2006 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Ward, Albert- Spanish Colonial Frontier Research, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Warren, Helene, 1981-1988 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Watson, Patty Jo, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Weaver, Thomas, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Weber, J. Cynthia, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Weist, Katherine, 1971-1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Western History Association, 1973-2002 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Whiting, Alfred, 1955-1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Who’s Who, 1969, 1978, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Widdison, Jerry, 2004-2006 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Wilcox, David, 1978, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Anita, 1972-1976 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Wirth Associates, 1979-1982 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Wright, Barton, 1952-1991 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Y, 1967-1992 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Yataco, Miryam, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Z, 1976, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Zamora, Margarita, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Series III: Writings, 1947-2009
  This series contains published and unpublished writings of Henry F. Dobyns. This series is divided into 7 subseries. The material is arranged alphabetically by title, then by date of writing. Some material is in Spanish. This series contains restrictions on materials in box 39 folder 12, box 43 folder 2, box 51 folder 12 and box 61 folder 3.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts, 1947-2009
    This subseries contains drafts of manuscripts. Boxes 26-57. This subseries contains restrictions on materials in Box 39, folder 12 box 43 folder 2 and box 51 folder 12.
    - 1491: In Search of Aboriginal America, 2003 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - 1540 A Temporal Slice of O’odham Time, undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - The 1775-1782 Smallpox Pandemic in North America, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - The Aboriginal “Epidemic region”, undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - The Aboriginal Indian Population of Florida, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Aboriginal Socio-Political Structure and the Ethnic Group Concept of the Pai of Northwestern Arizona, 1967, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Academic Applied Anthropology, undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Academic Applied Anthropology: Pioneers and Patterns, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Akimel O’odham, 2006, undated (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - The Alliance Makers: Native American Women, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Allotment, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Alluvial Springs in Piman Irrigation, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Almanac of Dates Significant to Native American History in the Southwestern United States, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 28-30)
    - Almanac of Southwestern Indians History, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Altitude Sorting of Ethnic Groups in the Southwest, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - The Amaranth and Nut Tree Solution to the Puzzle of Southeastern Native American Sedentarism, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Ancestors of the Arizona O’odham, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Andean Cultural Change Casebook, 1964-1971 (Box 27, Folder 1-6)
    - Andean Perspectives on the Ethnography of Writing, 1979-1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - An Annotated Bibliography of Southwestern and Native American Religious Shrines, Rock Cairns, Stacked rock features and Rock Markers, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Anthropological Appraisal Research, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Anthropological Theories of Water Utilization, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - The Anthropologist as Expert Witness, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Apache Allies appear at Spanish Tucson, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - An Apache Chronology of Migration and Crop Irrigation, 1992, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Apache Indian Fire-hunting Ethnohistorical Perspective on Environmental Management, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Apache Treaty: An Analysis of the 11 July 1852 Chihenne Band Chiricahua Treaty of Acoma Pueblo, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Apache: Treaty of Santa Fé, 1852, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Applied Anthropology: The Competence of Researchers Adequacy of Graduate Training Programs and Scientific Journal Review Procedures, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Applied Anthropology: My Personal Experience, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Applied Anthropology Over Seven Decades, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Appraisal Research and Applied Anthropology, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Are American Women Demanding Themselves out of Marriage?, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Arivaipa Creek, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Arizona Battles, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Arizona Battles, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
    - Arizona Battles, 1994-1995 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Battles, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Battles, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 6-8)
    - Arizona Indian Education, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Arizona’s Pinto Democrats, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Attracting Scholars’ Attention: When to Count Citations, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
    - Azul Family, 1984-1986 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - The Azul Family: Pima-Maricopa Confederation Leaders, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Bands of Gardeners, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - A Basketful of Blazing-Stars, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Beaver River: Traditional Akimel O’odham Natural Resource Management in the San Pedro River Watershed, Eastern Arizona, 1996-1997 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Big Game (and Fish) in Southern Arizona in 1846-1855, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Blood Groups in the American Southwest: Some Methodological Considerations of Interpretation, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - A Brief History of the Pima-Maricopa Confederation on Gila River Reservation, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - A Brief History of the Walapai Indians, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - A Brief Memoir Concerning Paul H. Ezell as Applied Anthropologist and Theoretician, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Building Stones and Paper Evidence of Native American Historical Numbers, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - The Camp File Experiment, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Carbohydrates in Native American Diets: A Reappraisal of the “Thrifty Genotype” Theory, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Casa Grande, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Casa Grande, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
    - Casa Grande, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Casa Grande’s Outstanding Women, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - The Case of the Burned out Water Pump, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The Case of the United States Public Health Service Attack on Navajo Diarrheas, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 15-16)
    - Case Studies of Native American Historic Epidemic Mortality Rates- Introduction, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Changing Riverscape, Changing River People, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Chickasaw Historic Demography, 1993-1995 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Chief Executive Succession in Peru 1821-1971, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Citation Index for Human Organization, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Clash of Cultures, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - The Climate of the Gila River Watershed during Spanish Colonial Times, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Cocolitztli, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - The Colonial Spanish Presidios at Tubac, 2003, 2004, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Colorado River Indian Reservation Tribal Histories, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Comment on “The Culture-Historical Configurations of the American Peoples”, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Comment on Dalton, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Comment on “Depopulation of the Central Andes in the 16th Century”, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Comment on Hydrographic Survey Report for San Pedro Watershed by Arizona Department of Water Resources, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Comment on “Migration, Agrarian Reform and Structural Change in Rural Peru”, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Comment on “The Scholar and the Troubled Citizen”, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Comment on Some Key Cultural Characteristics of the Aboriginal Southeast and Historic Changes There, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Comments on Atatsivwu Umanakwat Kaivyaxaruruvatuxw, From the Sands to the Mountain, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Comments on Cultural Blinders in Research on Native Horticulture Ecology Session, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Comments on Schlesier and White, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Commentary on “Intergroup Relations Inventory, Tucson, Arizona”, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Communities to Study: Abundant or Scarce?, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Comparative Rates of Cultural Change, undated (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Confederation History, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Confrontation of Europe and America, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Consequences of Enlightenment, undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Consequences of Northern Plains Historic Epidemiology, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Continuity of European Settlement in Southern Arizona, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - The Continuity of Legal Personnel in Globe Equity 59, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Conversion of Historic Spanish Borderlands: Landscapes into Industrial Landscapes, 1940-2000 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Corazones Trading Center Colonized, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Creating Commercial Extra-Long Staple Cotton by Exploiting Gila River Indian Reservation Natural and Human Resources, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 26-29)
    - Creating Commercial Extra-Long Staple Cotton by Exploiting Gila River Indian Reservation Natural and Human Resources, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 30-31)
    - Creating Commercial Extra-Long Staple Cotton by Exploiting Gila River Indian Reservation Natural and Human Resources, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
    - Creation and Expansion of Gila River Indian Reservation, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 4-6)
    - Critique of Social Organization of the Papago Indians by Ruth Murray Underhill as a model Ethnological Monograph, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Cultural Continuities and Changes among the Northern Piman Speaking Indians between 1100 AD and 1965 AD, 1963-1964 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Cultural Heritage of Wagering on the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Cultural Variations in Territoriality, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Cultural Transfer, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Danger: Detrimental to Understanding Southwestern Peoples, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Dates Significant to Native Americans, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Dating Mining Occupation at Guebavi, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Dating San Tadeo de vav komalik and its Pots, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - The Decline of Mescalero Apache Indian Population from 1873 to 1913, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Demographic Collapse: Indian Peru, 1520-1620, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Demographics of Native American History, 1981, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Devil’s Claw Basketry Use and Cultivation Analysis, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 19-20)
    - Diffusion of Cultural Catholicism on Mexico’s Northern Frontier, 1821-1846, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Dimensions of Dependency, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Direct European Immigrant Transmission of Old World Pathogens to Numic Indians during the Nineteenth Century, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Directed Culture Change in Latin America, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - The Discontinuity of Legal Personnel in Globe Equity 59, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - A Discussion of Anthropological Theory, undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Discussion of Rules and Events Significant for Identifying Accurate Dates of “Apparent First Use” of Water by Federal Agencies, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Disease Transfer at Contact, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Disease Transfer at Contact, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
    - Diseases essay for Encyclopedia of the American Indian, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Do-It-Yourself Religion: The Diffusion of Folk Catholicism on Mexico’s Northern Frontier, 1821-1846, 1981, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Don Antonio Comaduran: Tucson Presidio Commandant, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - The Dozen Pima Starving Years, 1892-1904, 1997-1998 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Dynamics of Hispanic Kinship in Southern Arizona, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - The Dynamics of North American Settlement, undated (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Dynamics of Settlement Patterning among Northern Piman Indians, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Early Historic Piman Population Collapse and Cultural Change, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Apache Ethnohistory, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Eastern Apaches, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Ecclesiastical Administration on the Northern Frontier of New Spain, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Ecological Stability and Instability in Modern Society, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Eight Essays Elucidating Piman Indian Environment and Culture, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 16-17)
    - Eight Essays Elucidating Piman Indian Environment and Culture, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Emerging Patterns of Ethnohistorical Instruction, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - The Encyclopedia of the American Indian- Diseases, 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - The Encyclopedia of the American Indian – Pai, 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Environmental Change at Tucson, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Environmental Consequences of Suburbanization in Prescot, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - The Epidemic Disease Mortality Model and the Importance of Accurate Mortality Rates and Regional Epidemic Chronologies, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Epidemics, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Epidemics in Pimería Alta, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Essays on the Historic Epidemiology of Native American Peoples, 1982, undated (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Essays on Historic Native American Epidemiology, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 28-29)
    - Estimating Aboriginal American Population, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Ethnic Differences in the Demography of the Frontier of New Spain, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Ethnic Migration in New Spain: A Summary, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ethnic Minglement on New Spain’s Northern Frontier, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Ethnic Mingling on New Spain’s Northern Frontier, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Ethnobotany, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Ethnohistorical Methods, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Ethnohistory, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Ethnohistory, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Ethnohistory Courses, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Ethnohistory Essays Spanish Borderlands, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - European Contact in North America, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - European Dietary Changes, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - European Migration and the Transmission of Disease to Native Americans, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - An Evaluation of Ethnohistory from a Colombian Quincentary Perspective, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - The Fairies Face Inflation, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - The Father-Daughter Relationship among Native Americans, 1985-1987 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Feeding Forty-Niners: Pima-Maricopa Response to Economic Opportunity in 1849, 1993-1995 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - The First Americans, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 17-19)
    - First Drop or Last?, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 20-22)
    - Forests in the Long Sweep of American History, undated (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 6-13)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 5-9)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 10-13)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Fortunes in Feathers, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Forty-three Years on the Spanish Colonial Frontier: Joseph Agustín de Campos, S.J., 1996 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Francis La Flesche, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - From Fire to Flood: Historic Human Destruction of Sonoran Desert Riverine Oasis, 2003 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - The Frontier Provinces, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Geographic Provenance of the US Anthropological Profession, ca. 1968 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - The Gila River Delta: Maricopa land and Water Use where the Salt River enters the Gila River, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Gila River Flows: A Reconstruction 1867-1896 and a Restoration of Natural Flow Thereafter, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Gila River Indian Community and the United States of America, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Gila River Indian Reservation Consumptive Water Use Model, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 11-12)
    - Gila River Indian Reservation Gila River “Natural Flow” water Consumption under the Gila River Decree (Globe Equity 59), 1987 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Gila River Pima Entrepreneurship, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 14-15)
    - The Gila River Pima-Maricopa Response to Economic Opportunity in 1849, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Gila River Pima-Maricopa Reponses to Historic Economic Opportunity and Disincentives, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 17-19)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 20-24)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
    - Gila River Valley Irrigation: A History of Differential Water Control and Economic Success, 1848-1990, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 6-8)
    - The Gila River Watershed Tributary Streams that Flowed under Indian Management, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Gileño Pima- Maricopa Responses to the 1849 Gold Rush, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Gileños: Miscellaneous Documents, undated (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - A Glimpse of Solon T. Kimball as Academic Leader of Self-Perceived Applied Anthropologists, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Globe Equity 59, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 13-15)
    - Globe Equity 59, 1998 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Globe Equity 59: Gila River Indian Reservation’s Limited Acreage Involved in the Gila River Decree, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Globe Equity 59: Hearing, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History of the Background of the Case, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History of the Case from 1925 Complaint to 1935 Gila River Decree, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
    - Globe Equity 59: A History of the Case from 1925 Complaint to 1935 Gila River Decree, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Governance of the University of Kentucky Today: A Professorial Assessment, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Governor Bernal and Father Campos, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Great Food, Forgettable People- Now that’s a Real- World Meal, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Groundwater Exploitation in the Upper Gila River Valleys: A Brief Historical Sketch, 1991-1994 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Hepah, California!, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Hereditary Bodily Deformations of Clinical Significance among the Many Farms Navaho: A Preliminary Statement, 1959 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Hispanic Persistence in the Pimeria Alta, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Historic Agricultural Commodity Prices in Arizona Territory, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Historic Apache Leadership, undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Historic Arizona Court Cases Concerning Water, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Historic Causative Factors in Native American Diabetes, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Historic Central Arizona Stream Flows, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Historic Changes in Habitat and Economic Patterns among the Kokololoti Tribe of Northern Piman-Speaking Indoamericans, undated (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Historic Changes in Irrigated Food and Fiber Plants Grown in Southern Arizona, undated (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - An Historic Chronology of Events in the Piman Region Pertinent to Archaeological Interpretation, undated (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Historic Havasupai Population Trends, 1972-1974 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Historic Havasupai Population Trends, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - A Historical and Functional Quantitative Evaluation of Anthropology Departments, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Historical Notes on the Magdalena and Alter Districts of Sonora, Mexico, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - A History of the Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 23-26)
    - A History of the Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 1-5)
    - A History of the Creation and Expansion of the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
    - History of the Settlement of Tubac on the Santa Cruz River, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Hit-and-Run Publishing, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Hopi, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - How Newman Peak Received its Name, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Restricted (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Huhu’ula Gypsies, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Human Powered Wheeled vehicles in temporal perspective, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Hydrologic Context of the Gila River Decree, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Hydrological Foundations of Piman Settlement, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - A Hypothetical Reconstruction of New World Variation in Atmospheric Carbon Content, undated (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - If not Bread, A Circus, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - The Importance of Los Esteros on the Pecos, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - India’s Minorities, undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Indian Individuals and Culture Change, undated (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Indian Novels, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 22-23)
    - Indian Reorganization Act and Federal Withdrawal, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Indians on the Run, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 25)